So, till now we have seen how Arleger framework works.
지금까지 우리는 Arleger 프레임워크가 어떻게 작동하는지 살펴보았습니다.
Now let's learn about some of its drawbacks.
이제 몇 가지 단점에 대해 알아 보겠습니다.
Firstly, training an additional reward model itself brings more complexity to the process.
첫째, 추가 보상 모델 자체를 교육하면 프로세스가 더 복잡해집니다.
This modeling step leads to careful tuning of additional hyperparameters.
이 모델링 단계에서는 추가 하이퍼파라미터를 신중하게 조정해야 합니다.
Furthermore, even though Arleger frameworks help us aligning the preferences, it can be
또한 Arleger 프레임워크가 기본 설정을 조정하는 데 도움이 되더라도
still sometimes less efficient and stable method.
여전히 때로는 덜 효율적이고 안정적인 방법입니다.
Overall, this is how Arleger framework works.
전반적으로 이것이 Arleger 프레임워크가 작동하는 방식입니다.
We have a given preference data, we use it to fit the reward model and later this reward
우리는 주어진 선호 데이터를 가지고 있으며, 이를 보상 모델에 맞추고 나중에 이 보상에 맞추는 데 사용합니다.
model is used for aligning our language model policy.
모델은 언어 모델 정책을 조정하는 데 사용됩니다.
But can we perform the alignment without reward model?
그런데 보상 모델 없이 정렬을 수행할 수 있나요?
Well, to answer this, DPO or DPO papers authors came up with a new technique that directly
글쎄요, 이에 답하기 위해 DPO 또는 DPO 논문 작성자는 직접적으로
uses the preference data for aligning it with the preference data.
기본 설정 데이터와 정렬하기 위해 기본 설정 데이터를 사용합니다.
So, simply put, DPO is a simple, Arleger-free algorithm for training language models from
간단히 말해서 DPO는 언어 모델을 훈련하기 위한 Arleger가 없는 간단한 알고리즘입니다.
preferences.
환경 설정.
So, to start with the DPO process, let's first go through how it actually came in place.
따라서 DPO 프로세스부터 시작하려면 먼저 DPO 프로세스가 실제로 어떻게 진행되었는지 살펴보겠습니다.
This is the optimization problem that we used for Arleger.
이것이 우리가 Arleger에 사용한 최적화 문제입니다.
Higher the reward for any response is considered better for the model because that is what
모든 응답에 대한 보상이 높을수록 모델에 더 나은 것으로 간주됩니다.
we intend to.
우리는 그럴 생각이다.
Also, this is the policy that we are trying to optimize.
또한 이것이 우리가 최적화하려는 정책입니다.
This is the reference policy and this is where we are trying to limit the deviation of the
이것이 참조 정책이며 여기서 우리는 편차를 제한하려고 합니다.
policy in training from reference policy.
참조 정책에서 학습하는 정책입니다.
So, basically we do not want our policy to deviate too much far away from the reference
따라서 기본적으로 우리는 정책이 참조에서 너무 많이 벗어나는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
policy otherwise it will tend to give us some illogical responses.
그렇지 않으면 우리에게 비논리적인 반응을 보이는 경향이 있습니다.
Here we have been using Kale divergence for limiting this similarity.
여기서 우리는 이러한 유사성을 제한하기 위해 케일 발산(Kale divergence)을 사용해 왔습니다.
Now, the authors came up with this optimal solution as shown here that is we have rewritten
이제 저자는 여기에 표시된 최적의 솔루션을 생각해 냈습니다.
the optimal solution in terms of reference policy, reward function and a partition function.
참조 정책, 보상 기능 및 분할 기능 측면에서 최적의 솔루션입니다.
Using some mathematical, normal mathematical algebra, we can also rewrite the reward function
수학적, 일반적인 수학 대수학을 사용하여 보상 함수를 다시 작성할 수도 있습니다.
in terms of optimal policy, reference policy and partition function, sorry.
최적의 정책, 참조 정책, 파티션 기능 측면에서 죄송합니다.
Based on this, we know now that if we have reward function in place, we can also write
이를 바탕으로 이제 보상 기능이 있으면 다음과 같이 작성할 수도 있다는 것을 알았습니다.
human preference probability using bodily model in terms of reference policy and optimal
참조 정책과 최적 측면에서 신체 모델을 이용한 인간 선호 확률
policy which we have here.
우리가 여기에 있는 정책입니다.
It is just here is the optimal policy, this is the reference policy.
바로 여기에 최적의 정책이 있고 이것이 참조 정책입니다.
Thus, now as we have the human preference probability in terms of optimal policy and
따라서 이제 우리는 최적의 정책과 측면에서 인간 선호 확률을 갖게 되었습니다.
reference policy, we can also rewrite our loss function in terms of it.
참조 정책을 사용하여 손실 함수를 다시 작성할 수도 있습니다.
Well, as we see here, this is pretty similar to what we already have with RLHF.
글쎄요, 여기서 볼 수 있듯이 이는 이미 RLHF에서 얻은 것과 매우 유사합니다.
We can see there is some positive operation with the winner response and some negative
승자의 반응에는 긍정적인 반응이 있고 부정적인 반응도 있는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
operation for the loser response.
패자 대응을 위한 작전.
Something similar that we had earlier, here we are operating something with winner response
이전에 했던 것과 비슷한 것, 여기서는 승자 응답으로 무언가를 운영하고 있습니다.
and negating for the loser response.
패자 응답을 부정합니다.
So, well, here we can see, here we are trying, first we are trying to maximize the probability
자, 여기서 볼 수 있듯이, 여기서는 우리가 노력하고 있습니다. 먼저 우리는 확률을 최대화하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
of the winner response and trying to minimize the probability for the loser response.
승자 응답의 확률을 최소화하고 패자 응답의 확률을 최소화하려고 노력합니다.
And also, as per the paper, authors has termed this particular fraction, this particular
그리고 또한 논문에 따르면 저자들은 이 특별한 부분을 이렇게 불렀습니다.
value as implicit reward.
암묵적인 보상으로서의 가치.
So this is also, we can say that it's also giving us the idea how actually the optimization
따라서 이것은 또한 실제로 최적화가 어떻게 이루어지는지에 대한 아이디어를 제공한다고 말할 수 있습니다.
is working.
일하고 있습니다.
It is trying to limit the deviation from the reference policy and it's also trying to maximize
참조 정책으로부터의 이탈을 제한하려고 노력하고 있으며 또한 최대화하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
the winner response, maximize the probability of the winner response and minimizing for
승자 반응의 확률을 최대화하고 승자 반응의 확률을 최소화합니다.
the loser response.
패자 반응.
Now, well, for in terms of the results, so authors have performed evaluations on multiple
이제 결과 측면에서 저자는 여러 가지에 대해 평가를 수행했습니다.
tests, multiple data sets and they've come up, they've compared with the original PPO
테스트, 여러 데이터 세트가 나오고 원래 PPO와 비교했습니다.
versus DPO, their new method.
새로운 방법 인 DPO와 비교합니다.
So this is task one, that is control sentiment generation.
이것이 작업 1, 즉 제어 감정 생성입니다.
So as you all know, goal of this task is given a movie review, we want to generate a positive
그래서 여러분도 아시다시피 이 작업의 목표는 영화 리뷰를 제공하는 것입니다.
sentiment response.
감정반응.
We can see here, for DPO, this is yellow one is DPO, it has, it is strictly dominating
여기에서 볼 수 있습니다. DPO의 경우 노란색이 DPO입니다. 엄격히 지배하고 있습니다.
when we compare it with PPO, the reward to KL divergence ratio.
KL 발산 비율에 대한 보상인 PPO와 비교할 때.
So as we see, even if the KL divergence between the optimal policy and the reference policy
따라서 우리가 볼 수 있듯이 최적 정책과 참조 정책 간의 KL 차이가 발생하더라도
is low, that means they are close enough and yet DPO gives us good high reward, which is
낮다는 것은 충분히 가깝지만 DPO가 우리에게 좋은 높은 보상을 제공한다는 것을 의미합니다.
good because in terms of, in case of PPO, we were not getting that good reward when policies
왜냐하면 PPO의 경우 정책을 시행할 때 좋은 보상을 받지 못했기 때문입니다.
are very similar to each other.
서로 매우 유사합니다.
And also, PPOGT, that is using the ground truth model, ground truth for the ground
또한 Ground Truth 모델을 사용하는 PPOGT는 Ground Truth입니다.
truth reward model for the sentiment analysis, when they are using that particular ground
특정 근거를 사용할 때 감정 분석을 위한 진실 보상 모델
truth, even then, they are not able to achieve good rewards with PPO.
사실 그렇다고 해도 PPO로는 좋은 보상을 얻을 수 없습니다.
So this shows how powerful DPO is in terms of evaluation and in terms of stability.
따라서 이는 평가 및 안정성 측면에서 DPO가 얼마나 강력한지를 보여줍니다.
Next is summarization.
다음은 요약입니다.
So for summarization, the task is given, given a Reddit post, we want to extract main points
요약을 위해 Reddit 게시물이 주어지면 주요 포인트를 추출하고 싶습니다.
of the sample, main points of the passage.
샘플의 주요 요점.
Well, this experiment is performed on varying, varying, varying sampling temperatures.
음, 이 실험은 다양하고, 다양하고, 다양한 샘플링 온도에서 수행됩니다.
As we can see, DPO, the yellow one is pretty much stable across all the sampling temperatures.
보시다시피 노란색 DPO는 모든 샘플링 온도에서 거의 안정적입니다.
Whereas for PPO, it is highly unstable, the efficiency is decreasing.
PPO의 경우 매우 불안정하고 효율성이 감소합니다.
So as we know, increasing the sampling temperature, it will lead to higher probabilistic results
우리가 알고 있듯이 샘플링 온도를 높이면 더 높은 확률적 결과를 얻을 수 있습니다.
and tend to give more unstable model.
더 불안정한 모델을 제공하는 경향이 있습니다.
But even with that, DPO is still performing pretty well when compared with PPO and as
하지만 그럼에도 불구하고 DPO는 PPO에 비해 여전히 좋은 성능을 보이고 있습니다.
well as if we compare it with best of 128, it is giving us comparative, comparable results.
그리고 128개 베스트와 비교해 보면 비교불가한 결과를 보여주고 있습니다.
So best of 128 as per the paper is when you are trying to extract 128 responses and just
따라서 논문에 따르면 128개 중 가장 좋은 것은 128개의 응답을 추출하려고 할 때입니다.
take best of it, like best responses.
최고의 답변처럼 최대한 활용하세요.
Taking, considering best of 128, so it could be pretty demanding, pretty computationally
128의 최고점을 고려하면 꽤 까다로울 수 있고 계산적으로도 꽤 까다로울 수 있습니다.
demanding method because we are trying to generate 120 responses and then figuring out
우리는 120개의 응답을 생성한 다음 알아내려고 노력하기 때문에 까다로운 방법입니다.
what's the correct answer.
정답은 무엇입니까?
Even with this scenario, task three, it's single turn dialogue where we are giving
이 시나리오, 작업 3에서도 우리가 제공하는 것은 단일 턴 대화입니다.
human query and we want to get a proper response from the LLM.
인간의 질의로 인해 LLM으로부터 적절한 응답을 받고 싶습니다.
Even with this case, DPO is performing pretty good and comparable enough with best of 128,
이 경우에도 DPO는 꽤 좋은 성능을 보이고 있으며 최고 128과 충분히 비교할 수 있습니다.
such highly computationally demanding method.
계산량이 매우 많은 방법입니다.
This shows that DPO is working quite well on different tasks.
이는 DPO가 다양한 작업에서 매우 잘 작동하고 있음을 보여줍니다.
Authors of the people analyzed the performance of the model over the course of the training
People의 작성자는 훈련 과정에서 모델의 성능을 분석했습니다.
steps.
단계.
As we can see here, the model remains fairly stable even for different sampling temperatures
여기서 볼 수 있듯이 모델은 다양한 샘플링 온도에서도 상당히 안정적으로 유지됩니다.
for the strain steps.
변형 단계의 경우.
As we see here, overall, it is pretty much stable for different sampling temperatures.
여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 전반적으로 다양한 샘플링 온도에 대해 거의 안정적입니다.
Even converges readily quickly for both sampling temperatures.
두 샘플링 온도 모두에 대해 쉽게 빠르게 수렴됩니다.
This shows how DPO is much more stable and efficient method for aligning the language
이는 DPO가 언어 정렬을 위한 훨씬 더 안정적이고 효율적인 방법임을 보여줍니다.
model.
모델.
So that's all for DPO paper.
이것이 DPO 용지의 전부입니다.
Moving on, next paper that we are going to talk about is the file.
계속해서 우리가 이야기할 다음 논문은 파일입니다.
The key highlights of this paper are that the model has used different AI models for
이 문서의 주요 하이라이트는 모델이 다양한 AI 모델을 사용했다는 것입니다.
generating the preference data and also a unique distillation method is used for curating
선호도 데이터를 생성하고 큐레이팅을 위해 독특한 증류 방식을 사용합니다.
good dataset for fine-tuning.
미세 조정을 위한 좋은 데이터 세트
So this is how Zafire training looks like.
이것이 Zafire 훈련의 모습입니다.
We have already seen how Instructivity training looks like.
우리는 이미 교육 훈련이 어떻게 진행되는지 살펴보았습니다.
This is in a similar format.
이것도 비슷한 형식입니다.
We have divided the training steps in three parts.
우리는 훈련 단계를 세 부분으로 나누었습니다.
First we have the fine-tuning step, which is the still fine-tuning.
먼저 미세 조정 단계가 있는데, 이는 아직 미세 조정 단계입니다.
So the goal here is to curate a good high-quality response that will be able to capture the
따라서 여기에서의 목표는
capabilities of the teacher model.
교사 모델의 능력
So teacher model that was used for Zafire training is GPT-4.
따라서 Zafire 교육에 사용된 교사 모델은 GPT-4입니다.
As we see here, we have some initial seed prompts and our aim is to curate this dataset
여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 몇 가지 초기 시드 프롬프트가 있으며 목표는 이 데이터 세트를 선별하는 것입니다.
using teacher model.
교사 모델을 사용합니다.
Now we do that.
이제 우리는 그렇게 합니다.
Let's say we take one of the seed prompt, we pass it to a teacher model, then generate
시드 프롬프트 중 하나를 가져와 이를 교사 모델에 전달한 다음 생성한다고 가정해 보겠습니다.
the response.
응답.
As we have the response, we pass both the prompt and the response to the teacher model
응답이 있으면 프롬프트와 응답을 모두 교사 모델에 전달합니다.
and tell it instructed to refine the instruction.
그리고 명령을 개선하도록 지시했습니다.
So we continue this process for a couple of steps and then we can generate a good high-quality
따라서 우리는 이 프로세스를 몇 단계 동안 계속한 다음 좋은 고품질 제품을 생성할 수 있습니다.
response dataset.
응답 데이터 세트.
This dataset will be used further for fine-tuning our model.
이 데이터 세트는 모델을 미세 조정하는 데 추가로 사용됩니다.
That is what we call the first fine-tuning step.
이것이 우리가 첫 번째 미세 조정 단계라고 부르는 것입니다.
We generated dataset, we curated dataset actually and then use it for fine-tuning the language
데이터 세트를 생성하고 실제로 데이터 세트를 큐레이팅한 다음 이를 언어 미세 조정에 사용합니다.
model.
모델.
So that's what we have.
그래서 그것이 우리가 가진 것입니다.
Ultrajet is the dataset that was generated and then we use it for fine-tuning the model.
Ultrajet은 생성된 데이터 세트이며 이를 모델 미세 조정에 사용합니다.
That's what we call distillation supervised fine-tuning.
이것이 바로 우리가 증류 감독 미세 조정이라고 부르는 것입니다.
Now, moving on to the second step that is response generation and air ranking.
이제 두 번째 단계인 반응 생성 및 공기 순위로 넘어갑니다.
So this step 2 includes using of a teacher model again and same teacher model was used
따라서 이 2단계에는 교사 모델을 다시 사용하는 것이 포함되며 동일한 교사 모델이 사용되었습니다.
with this step 2 and generating generation of preference data using other models.
이 2단계를 통해 다른 모델을 사용하여 선호도 데이터를 생성합니다.
So how we do that?
그럼 어떻게 할까요?
We use a prompt, we pass it to four different language models and then we ask them to generate
우리는 프롬프트를 사용하여 이를 네 가지 다른 언어 모델에 전달한 다음 생성하도록 요청합니다.
a response.
응답.
Each of them generate a response and teacher model is used for scoring the response.
각각은 응답을 생성하고 교사 모델은 응답을 채점하는 데 사용됩니다.
We have this thing.
우리에겐 이런 것이 있습니다.
S1 is the first score where model is trying to evaluate based on the prompt and the response
S1은 모델이 프롬프트와 응답을 기반으로 평가하려는 첫 번째 점수입니다.
and score it accordingly.
그리고 그에 따라 점수를 매기세요.
Once we have the scores ready, we will curate a dataset that is that consists of the prompt
점수가 준비되면 프롬프트로 구성된 데이터 세트를 선별합니다.
that was used, the winner response with the highest score and a loser response.
가장 높은 점수를 받은 승자 응답과 패자 응답이 사용되었습니다.
Now the catch here is for the loser response we have not selected the model, the response
이제 여기서 중요한 점은 모델을 선택하지 않은 패자 응답에 대한 것입니다.
with the least score, rather we randomly select one of the response from the remaining
가장 낮은 점수로 나머지 응답 중 하나를 무작위로 선택합니다.
three candidates.
세 명의 후보.
So this was the chosen approach because they wanted to include diversity in the dataset.
따라서 데이터 세트에 다양성을 포함하기를 원했기 때문에 이것이 선택된 접근 방식이었습니다.
So that is what we have with this second step.
이것이 바로 이 두 번째 단계입니다.
We sample prompts, we pass it to different models and use GPT4 for binarization.
프롬프트를 샘플링하여 다른 모델에 전달하고 이진화를 위해 GPT4를 사용합니다.
This dataset that was generated is also named as ultrafeedback.
생성된 이 데이터세트는 울트라피드백이라고도 합니다.
Now moving to third step that is DPU.
이제 세 번째 단계인 DPU로 이동합니다.
So DPU we have already seen how DPU works and Zephyr is model that is utilizing DPU
그래서 DPU 우리는 이미 DPU가 어떻게 작동하는지 살펴봤고 Zephyr는 DPU를 활용하는 모델입니다.
method for aligning the language model with the feedback data.
언어 모델을 피드백 데이터와 정렬하는 방법.
So the training procedure is pretty simple.
따라서 훈련 절차는 매우 간단합니다.
We perform, we calculate the probability of winner response and loser response with respect
우리는 승자 응답과 패자 응답의 확률을 계산합니다.
to the fine tune model that we got with first step.
첫 번째 단계에서 얻은 미세 조정 모델에 적용합니다.
Then we also try to get, we get a probability from DPU model that we are trying to update
그런 다음 업데이트하려는 DPU 모델로부터 확률을 얻으려고 합니다.
and then back propagate using this equation, we have already seen how we got this one, maximization
그런 다음 이 방정식을 사용하여 역전파합니다. 우리는 이미 이 방정식을 어떻게 얻었는지 보았습니다.
of the winner response and minimizing for the loser response.
승자 응답을 최소화하고 패자 응답을 최소화합니다.
This is same as what we have already learned with DPU.
이는 우리가 이미 DPU에서 배운 것과 동일합니다.
To look at some of the training details, the fine tuning experiments were performed on
훈련 세부 사항 중 일부를 살펴보기 위해 미세 조정 실험이 수행되었습니다.
Western 7B.
서부 7B.
So this is the state of the art model for 7 billion size category models.
따라서 이것은 70억 크기 범주 모델에 대한 최첨단 모델입니다.
So that's why authors chose this model.
그래서 저자는 이 모델을 선택했습니다.
They've also used a transformer reinforcement learning library for fine tuning and for optimizing
또한 미세 조정 및 최적화를 위해 변압기 강화 학습 라이브러리를 사용했습니다.
memory and improving the training speed, they've used deep speed 03 and flesh attention mechanisms.
기억력과 훈련 속도를 향상시키기 위해 딥 스피드 03과 육체 주의 메커니즘을 사용했습니다.
Now moving forward to the evaluation part, multiple data sets were used for evaluation
이제 평가 부분으로 넘어가서 여러 데이터 세트를 평가에 사용했습니다.
purpose.
목적.
Here is the gist of the data set.
데이터 세트의 요지는 다음과 같습니다.
One, first it was empty bench that has multi-tune response benchmark, it includes 160 questions
하나, 먼저 다중 조정 응답 벤치마크가 있는 빈 벤치였으며, 160개의 질문이 포함되어 있습니다.
across eight different areas of knowledge.
8가지 지식 분야에 걸쳐
Mainly it has one initial question, model is supposed to respond to that and it has
주로 하나의 초기 질문이 있고 모델은 이에 응답해야 하며
a predefined second response, second question is a follow up question and then that is how
미리 정의된 두 번째 응답, 두 번째 질문은 후속 질문입니다.
model will generate second response and then GPT-4 will be used for evaluating the combination
모델은 두 번째 응답을 생성한 다음 GPT-4를 사용하여 조합을 평가합니다.
of the responses.
응답의.
There's one more that is Alpaca event that is a singleton benchmark.
싱글톤 벤치마크인 Alpaca 이벤트가 하나 더 있습니다.
It includes 805 questions across different topics, mostly that's focused on helpfulness
다양한 주제에 걸쳐 805개의 질문이 포함되어 있으며 대부분 유용성에 중점을 두고 있습니다.
and here also GPT-4 is used for evaluations.
여기에서도 GPT-4가 평가에 사용됩니다.
But here we perform pairwise-winded comparison.
하지만 여기서는 pairwise-winded 비교를 수행합니다.
So as we see here for both the metrics, Zephyr outperforms the 7 billion size model category
여기에서 두 지표 모두에 대해 볼 수 있듯이 Zephyr는 70억 크기 모델 카테고리보다 성능이 뛰어납니다.
and it provides highest scores, yeah, you can see here.
가장 높은 점수를 제공합니다. 예, 여기에서 볼 수 있습니다.
Also, if we compare it with some of the higher size data sets, even it is out matching them
또한 더 큰 크기의 일부 데이터 세트와 비교하면 일치하지 않더라도
and if we compare it with GPT-4, it is still giving us pretty comparable results that shows
GPT-4와 비교해 보면 여전히 꽤 비슷한 결과를 보여줍니다.
how much well trained this model is, even if it's such a small size model.
이렇게 작은 모델이더라도 이 모델이 얼마나 잘 훈련되었는지 알 수 있습니다.
One thing to note here is that Alpaca event results could be somewhat misleading because
여기서 주의할 점은 알파카 이벤트 결과가 다소 오해의 소지가 있을 수 있다는 점입니다.
the data set doesn't involve a huge variety of the questions that are needed to be evaluated.
데이터 세트에는 평가에 필요한 다양한 질문이 포함되어 있지 않습니다.
So this is what we do for evaluation with the empty benchmark bench.
따라서 이것이 빈 벤치마크 벤치를 사용하여 평가하기 위해 수행하는 작업입니다.
It has questions across different domains and we can also divide it across them and as
다양한 영역에 걸쳐 질문이 있으며 이를 여러 영역으로 나눌 수도 있습니다.
we see here, Zephyr performs very good and comparative enough for multiple categories
여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 Zephyr는 여러 카테고리에서 매우 훌륭하고 비교 가능한 성능을 발휘합니다.
like role play, writing, humanities, STEM, even with extraction.
역할극, 글쓰기, 인문학, STEM, 심지어 추출까지 말이죠.
But it performs very bad when it's about coding or math.
하지만 코딩이나 수학에 관해서는 성능이 매우 나쁩니다.
It's even worse than most of the models.
대부분의 모델보다 훨씬 나쁩니다.
So we should have this thing in mind, what area or what thing that we are trying to use
그러므로 우리는 어떤 영역이나 어떤 것을 사용하려고 하는지 염두에 두어야 합니다.
the model for and then we can use appropriate model.
모델을 선택한 다음 적절한 모델을 사용할 수 있습니다.
So one thing to note that is we should keep in mind which area we are working on and which
따라서 한 가지 주목해야 할 점은 우리가 어떤 영역에서 작업하고 있는지, 어떤 영역을 염두에 두어야 한다는 것입니다.
model excels in that area.
모델은 그 분야에서 탁월합니다.
Next for evaluations, different open LLM leaderboards were also used.
다음 평가를 위해 다양한 공개 LLM 리더보드도 사용되었습니다.
Usually these are academic type data sets, how like multi-class classification questions.
일반적으로 이는 다중 클래스 분류 질문과 같은 학문적 유형의 데이터 세트입니다.
Even with this data sets, we can see that Zephyr is outperforming the seven million
이 데이터 세트를 통해서도 Zephyr가 700만 개를 능가한다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
size category and as well as it is giving good competition to even higher size models.
크기 카테고리뿐만 아니라 더 큰 크기의 모델과도 좋은 경쟁을 벌이고 있습니다.
You can see that it is almost giving similar results to good high sized models.
좋은 사이즈의 모델들과 거의 비슷한 결과를 보여주고 있음을 알 수 있습니다.
Now one more evaluation study was provided by the authors of Zephyr to understand how
이제 Zephyr의 저자는 또 다른 평가 연구를 제공하여
much the optimization was helpful, how much distillation was helpful for the Zephyr training.
최적화가 얼마나 도움이 되었는지, Zephyr 훈련에 얼마나 많은 증류가 도움이 되었는지를 보여줍니다.
So they have performed these four steps, four step training process.
그래서 그들은 이 네 단계, 네 단계 훈련 과정을 수행했습니다.
First directly use the Mr. Model and fine tune it using DPO for one epoch using the
먼저 Mr. Model을 직접 사용하고
ultrafeedback data set and as we see the distillation step was not performed and it has highly
울트라피드백 데이터 세트와 우리가 볼 수 있듯이 증류 단계는 수행되지 않았으며 매우
affected the model performance.
모델 성능에 영향을 미쳤습니다.
Next the fine tuning step was performed using ultrajet for one epoch and we can see a good
다음으로 한 epoch 동안 ultrajet을 사용하여 미세 조정 단계를 수행했으며 좋은 결과를 볼 수 있습니다.
increase in the results which shows us how much effective the data set is and how much
데이터 세트가 얼마나 효과적인지, 얼마나 효과적인지 보여주는 결과가 증가합니다.
it helps the model for correctly predicting the answers.
모델이 답을 정확하게 예측하는 데 도움이 됩니다.
Next we did perform one epoch of fine tuning using ultrajet and second epoch of ultrafeedback
다음으로 우리는 울트라젯을 사용하여 한 단계의 미세 조정을 수행하고 두 번째 단계의 울트라피드백을 수행했습니다.
and we see a little drop in the performance.
성능이 약간 저하되는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
So that's not good for the model and finally we performed one step of fine tuning using
따라서 이는 모델에 좋지 않으며 마지막으로 다음을 사용하여 한 단계의 미세 조정을 수행했습니다.
ultrajet and one step of DPO using ultrafeedback and that gives us maximum results which shows
울트라젯과 울트라피드백을 이용한 DPO 원스텝은 우리에게 최대의 결과를 보여줍니다.
that indeed DPO and distillation both are helping our model for improving its understanding
실제로 DPO와 증류는 모두 모델의 이해를 향상시키는 데 도움이 됩니다.
and aligning the preference data.
그리고 선호도 데이터를 정렬합니다.
Yes, that's all for Zephyr, thank you.
예, Zephyr에게는 그게 전부입니다. 감사합니다.